AMLAK BEFEKADU

AMLAKBARKON@GMAIL.COM

WASHINGTON D.C (240)505-9523

US CITIZEN AND AUTHORIZED TO WORK IN THE US FOR ANY EMPLOYER

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATION

Experienced Full Stack web Developer with a passion for all aspects of web development. Extensively well versed in both frontend and backend development, specializing in JavaScript, ruby, HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, API, Ajax, Angular, React, Redux JS, Node JS, MySQL, Java.

SUMMARY OF SOFT SKILLS

- Highly motivated to achieve set goals;
- Proactive, initiative and highly motivated individual with high attention to detail;
- Able to think out of the box, strong analytical, technical and problem solving skill;
- Able to work effectively within a team environment.

RELATED WORK EXPERIENCE

Participated in a thirteen-week full-stack web development immersive course, covering the fundamentals of programming languages, front-and back-end frameworks, and up-and-coming methodologies.

Produced independent portfolio of projects including:

- Tower of Hanoi: A mathematical puzzle where the objective is to move a stack of discs from one rod to another. Utilizing three rules: only one disk can be moved at a time, every move involves taking the top disk from one of the stacks and placing it on top of another stack, and no disk can be put on top of a smaller disk, the user can win the game
- Soccer League Full Stack Application: Utilized an ORM to create a database table structure and interact with stored relational data built in Rails.
- The Match: Constructed a backend API with two models utilizing SPA with an Angular Frontend and Rails Back-end methodology.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Java Developer at Lawson IT Consulting

2015 - 2017

- Worked on Axis implementation and used SOAPUI to test the SOAP.
- Worked on XML, XSD and XSLT to parse the request and create the new one based on the specification.
- Developed generic Java packages to produce and consume JMS messages through topics and queues in asynchronous message processing with guaranteed delivery.
- Responsible for writing JUnit test cases and Peer level testing.
- Extensively used JQuery selectors, events, Traversal and Jquery, AJAX with JSON Objects.

Jr. Full Stack Javascript Developer at Sun Taxi Cab Company

2013 - 2015

- Supported a Java based web application for the company.
- Participated in daily Scrum meetings and gained first-hand experience in an agile development environment.
- Assisted collecting information about the various software and products used in supporting our applications.

- Updated scripts, fixed external bugs, and obtained programming experience through short assignments.
- Investigated new technologies for future upgrades to specific applications
- Java binding was done in web API.
- Responsible for overall design & analysis Oracle ADF and integration with existing J2EE

Web Developer at Potomac Services Inc.

2010 - 2013

- Followed agile methodologies with sprint planning to monitor\update the status.
- Gathered requirements from the client for designing the Web Pages.
- Involved in Analysis, Design, Coding and Development of custom Interfaces.
- Developed the presentation layer using Model View Architecture implemented by Spring MVC.
- Developed Rest Web services for authentication and authorization.
- Implemented Front controller using Spring MVC framework.
- Participated in designing the user interface for the application using HTML, DHTML, Servlet, and JavaScript.
- Developed the war/ear file using Ant script and deployed into Tomcat Server.
- Used STS for code development along with GIT, Gerrit and perforce for managing the code.
- Wrote SQL Queries to get the information from Database, Saving the data, modifying the data in the Database, and removing the data from the Database.
- Used log4j logger system to maintain application logs.
- Performed unit testing and system testing.

Freelance Java\Web Developer

2008 -Present

- Created all types of Web Sites.
- Developed fully functional websites on Drupal platform.
- Interacted with the clients and visitors to solicit feedbacks on website and application designs and implemented possible changes suggested by them.
- Maintain new and existing websites and provide technical assistance for troubleshooting and upgrading.
- Create graphical and textual contents for websites and applications.
- Design GUI for websites and test them for cross browser comparability.

EDUCATION

B.S. Computer Science University of District of Columbia

May 2008

CERTIFICATIONS AND TRAINING

Web Development Immersive Student at General Assembly,

Jun 2017

COMPUTER SKILLS

Skills: SKILLS: C#.NET, VB.NET, .NET Framework 2.0/3.5/4/4.5/4.6, MS .NET Core, Classic ASP, ASP.NET, MVC 3/4/5, Entity Framework, NHibernate, LINQ, HTML/HTML5, CSS/CSS3, Bootstrap, PHP, WordPress, AJAX, JavaScript, jQuery, angular.js, XML, Web API, WCF, RESTful, Web Services.

REFERENCES

Available upon request